Palaksh Rungta, Senior at UC San Diego

ABOUT ME

I am a solution oriented person who loves to go out of their way to understand and solve problems with clear communication. Being from a **computer science**, **data science**, and **cognitive science** background, I bring a plethora of interdisciplinary expertise and critical thinking into my work!

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, SAN DIEGO (UCSD)

Bachelors of Science in Cognitive Science with a specialization in Machine Learning

Graduation in June 2022 | Cumulative GPA: 3.7 / 4.0 | Major GPA: 3.8 / 4.0

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

Python, Java, C++, SQL, MongoDB

EXPERIENCED IN

Supervised Machine Learning, Deep Learning (GAN, CNN, RNN), Data Structures, Computer Vision, Web Scraping, Natural Language Processing (NLP), APIs, Data Analysis, Data Visualization

ALGORITHMS PROFICIENT WITH

Neural Networks, Linear and Logistic Regression, SVM, KNN, Random Forest, Text-to-speech models

TOOLS & PACKAGES WORKED WITH

Git, Linux, Jupyter, Scipy, Tensorflow, Keras, Sci-kit learn, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Tacotron

EXPERIENCE

Price.com

DATA SCIENCE AND MACHINE LEARNING INTERN

JUN 2021 - PRESENT

- Experimented with various APIs and queried the results on MongoDB to increase the coverage of multiple fields by up to 83% which improved the model accuracy by 9%.
- Used SQL queries to fix around **80**% of the outdated product links found in all of the company's blogs into a new format in under **3 hours**.

FinBit.io - An Envestnet Yodlee Company

DATA SCIENCE INTERN

OCT 2020 - DEC 2020

- Applied multiple algorithms to recognize and group users with a 98.6% success rate to avoid duplicate entries and reduce the runtime drastically.
- Extracted user location data for **47**% of the users from just manual bank entries.
- Used various types of transaction information to predict the salary amount for **73**% of users.
- Received appreciation from the Founder/CEO for improving coverage and performance.

Nimber Inc.

BUSINESS AND MARKETING INTERN

APR 2019 - OCT 2019

 Performed market research, competitor analysis, SWOT analysis, and product pricing to arrive at a presentable investor pitch.

- Contributed in designing and framing content on platforms like Instagram, Facebook, etc. Worked with the UX team on website design and content.
- Signed up **The Design Lab** at UCSD as the **first customer** for Nimber Inc.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Comparison of Supervised Learning Algorithms

(CLICK ME FOR LINK)

- A comparison study to measure the performance of supervised learning algorithms **Random** Forest, Logistic Regression, and Artificial Neural Networks using hyperparameter tuning.
- Statistical metrics used were accuracy, F-score, and ROC AUC curve over 4 datasets.
- Found **Random Forest** performing the best (**89.9**% across all metrics tested).

Bar Locations and DUI cases

(CLICK ME FOR LINK)

- Examined the correlation between <u>Bar locations</u> and <u>DUI accidents</u> in San Diego.
- Used various **APIs**, **Geo-spatial analysis**, **Bootstrapping**, and various Machine Learning algorithms such as **SVM** and **K-Nearest Neighbors** to explore the correlation.
- Found **no significant correlation** after hypothesis testing using bootstrapping.

Safe N' Sound - SD Hacks 2019

(CLICK ME FOR LINK)

 Deployed a computer vision (OpenCV) application to reduce distractions while driving by recognizing the driver from their co-passengers and alerting them based on their facial features.

RESEARCH AND CO-CURRICULARS

Dr. Rose Yu's COVID-19 Deep Learning Lab

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

APR 2021 - PRESENT

- Running weekly CDC predictions of death rates using the **DeepGLEAM** deep learning model.
- Used their model to also predict hospitalization rates along with mortality rates for the CDC.

ACM AI Projects Team

APR 2021 - JUN 2021

 Deploying a Tacotron based text-to-speech model that can blend different accent prosody information using GANs.

Rotaract at UCSD | Student Organization

ACTIVITIES COMMITTEE MEMBER
MEMBERSHIP DIRECTOR. 2021 - 2022

JAN 2021 - JUN 2021 JUN 2021 - PRESENT